(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Congrats Birthday FOX
Shirakami Fubuki Happy Birthday 2021
Are you Ready?
2021.10.5
Shirakami Fubuki pre.
3D BirthdayLive!
Shirakami Fubuki
白上フブキ
Are you ready?
ギミー！レボリューション
作詞：こだまさおり　作曲：田淵智也
Gimme! Revolution
Lyrics: Saori Kodama / Composition: Tomoya Tabuchi
いえーい！早速1曲目行っちゃいましょう！
Yay! Let's go for the first song right away!
Tell me why 君に問いたい
Tell me why, I want to ask you
その熱い情熱の進化
About the evolution of that hot passion
待って！違和感の理由
Wait! The reason for this strange feeling
恋じゃまだ弱いな
If it's just love, it's still weak
100通りな好きが飽和しても
Even if a hundred kinds of "like" are saturated
なりたいのはOnly One
I want to be the Only One
思わず成長してく
Unintentionally growing
この感情は普通？
Is this feeling normal?
君がちゃんと振り向いてくれたら
If you would turn around properly
きっとそれが完成形
Surely that would be the complete form
理屈じゃ（理屈じゃ）
By logic (by logic)
なんとか（なんとか）
Somehow (somehow)
ここらで読んだ言葉より
More than the words read around here
めいっぱい（せーの！）
To the fullest (Ready, go!)
背伸びした初めての挑戦かもね
It might be a challenge, my first time stretching myself
You're the Next Star!
Tell me why 君に問いたい
Tell me why, I want to ask you
その熱い情熱の進化
About the evolution of that hot passion
そう君が君である存在が
Yes, your existence as yourself
語る未来 運命
Tells of the future and destiny
ほら
See,
なんでもできそう
I feel like I can do anything.
YOU ARE MY HERO
TAKE ME HIGH
君と目指すの あの遥か
Aiming for that distant place with you,
情熱のパラダイス
a paradise of passion.
もう 君が君でなきゃ
If you weren't you,
この星がピンチなんだよ
this planet would be in a pinch.
BABY
ねぇ いつか言わせて
Hey, let me say it someday,
ときめきが生み出す言葉
the words born from this heartbeat.
それを 愛とリンクしちゃおう
Let's link that with love.
大人未満 私の革命
Less than an adult, my revolution.
Wow!
Go, go!
どっち？
Which way?
Oh my god!
OK!
Come on!
いつだって今が最高でしょ READY GO!
Right now is always the best, right? READY GO!
はい！ということで！皆様！どうですか！盛り上がってますか！
Alright! So! Everyone! How are you doing? Are you hyped up?!
このあともいっぱいいっぱい歌いますからねー！
I'll be singing a lot more after this, okay!
ねぇ 教えて 聞かせて
Hey, tell me, let me hear it.
これからどうなるの？
What's going to happen from here?
これ以上ないくらい
More than anything else,
ときめきが加速しちゃうよ
my heart is starting to race.
Only THE STAR 遥か 目覚めてく
Only the star, distant, waking up.
私たちだけのカタチ
A shape that's only ours.
Tell me why 君に問いたい
Tell me why, I want to ask you,
その熱い情熱の進化
the evolution of that hot passion.
さぁ 君が君である存在が
Now, the fact that you are you,
語る未来 BABY
speaks of the future, baby.
ねぇ もっと知りたい
Hey, I want to know more,
この胸が高鳴る仕組み
the mechanism that makes my heart pound.
もはや 恋さえ凌駕しちゃう
It even surpasses love now,
新しい革命の予感
a premonition of a new revolution.
今日も SOS 駆けつけて来てね HERO レスキュー！
Come running to the SOS today too, Hero, rescue!
おい！おい！おい！おい！
Oi! Oi! Oi! Oi!
はい！ということで！はい！１曲目からテンション上がっちゃいました！
Alright! So! Yes! I've been hyped up since the first song!
ということで皆様、こんきーつね！白上フブキでございます！はいフレンズ！
So everyone, Konkitsune! It's Shirakami Fubuki! Hi friends!
はぁー、テンション上がったー！
Phew, I'm so hyped up!
はい、そうですね、今日ですね、今回、
Yes, well, today, this time,
白上フブキお誕生日イベント
thank you for coming to Shirakami Fubuki's birthday event,
「Congrats Birthday FOX」にお越しいただきありがとうございます！
"Congrats Birthday FOX"!
いやもう本当に一人ぼっち緊張する...
Man, I'm really nervous being all alone...
いつも一人でこうやってあの、
It's my first time doing a solo live
YouTubeでソロライブやるの初めてなので、もうめちゃめちゃ緊張してますわ。
on YouTube like this by myself, so I'm super duper nervous.
なんですけども、早速２曲目行ってみたいと思います。
But anyway, I'd like to move on to the second song right away.
聴いてください、ガーネット・ムーン。
Please listen to: Garnet Moon.
Garnet Moon / 作詞: 六ツ見純代 / 作曲: 迫 茂樹
Garnet Moon / Lyrics: Sumiyo Mutsumi / Composition: Shigeki Sako
髪に刺した赤い薔薇は 情熱の色
The red rose in my hair is the color of passion,
私を見たあなたまるで 熱いマタドール
You, looking at me, are like a passionate matador.
きらびやかに舞い踊れば 高鳴る胸
If I dance brilliantly, my heart pounds,
二度と来ない時の色を 染めるエピソード
an episode that colors the time that will never come again.
燃える 想い 奏でる ギター
Burning thoughts, a playing guitar...
愛しさを紡ぐでしょう
It will spin a tale of love, right?
旅人の傷跡痛むのなら 私の胸で眠りなさい
If your traveler's scars ache, sleep on my breast.
慈しみながら 包んで
While cherishing, I'll embrace,
あなただけ照らすの 今宵の月のように
and illuminate only you, like tonight's moon.
夢を探すあなたは行く 荒野の果て
You, searching for dreams, go to the end of the wasteland.
夢も見せるわ 私は今 孤独の海
I'll even show you dreams. I am now in a sea of solitude.
黒い靴脱ぎ ステップ踏んで
Taking off my black shoes, I take a step.
悲しみも 癒しましょう
Let's heal even the sadness.
旅人よ 明日に迷う夜は 私の胸に帰りなさい
Oh traveler, on nights you lose your way to tomorrow, return to my breast.
悲しみ知るほど 潤う月は 今日も輝く ひらひら揺れながら
The moon, moist with the more sadness it knows, shines today too, swaying flutteringly.
燃える想い 奏でるギター
A burning feeling, the guitar plays.
満たされなさを 紡ぐでしょう
It will probably weave the feeling of unfulfillment.
旅人よ 明日に迷う夜は 私の胸に帰りなさい
Oh traveler, on nights you lose your way to tomorrow, return to my breast.
悲しみ知るほど 潤う月は 今日も輝く ひらひら揺れながら
The moon, moist with the more sadness it knows, shines today too, swaying flutteringly.
旅人よ 傷跡痛むのなら 私の胸で眠りなさい
Oh traveler, if your scars ache, sleep in my breast.
慈しみながら 包んで あなただけ 照らすの 今宵の月のように
Enveloping with affection, I'll shine only on you, like tonight's moon.
恋空予報 / 作詞・作曲: koyori
Renku Yohou / Lyrics & Composition: koyori
ドキ ドキ ドキ しちゃってる
My heart's going throb, throb, throb.
あいつは 全然 気づかないな
That guy doesn't notice at all.
本当は もっと 話したいのに
I actually want to talk more, but...
しつこいなんて 思われてもな
I'm worried he might think I'm annoying.
授業中も 上の空だし
In class, my mind's elsewhere too.
こんなの 悔しいけど 仕方ないな
This is frustrating, but it can't be helped.
恋空予報 かなわないかも
The love sky forecast might not come true.
晴れのち曇りで 雨が降るでしょう
It'll probably be sunny, then cloudy, then rainy.
あいつの笑顔 いつも見とれて
Always staring blankly at his smile,
私 本日 恋してる模様
It seems I'm in love today.
ほら ほら もたもたしてると
Look, look, if you dally,
あっと言う間に あいつは帰るぞ
That guy will go home in the blink of an eye.
今までずっと 言えなかったけど
I haven't been able to say it until now, but...
本当はずっと 好きだったから
Because I've actually liked you all along.
答えは待って すぐに言わないで
Wait for the answer, don't say it right away.
耳をふさぎたくて ただ怖くて
I want to cover my ears, I'm just scared.
恋空予報 叶えてお願い
Love sky forecast, please come true.
雨が降ってるけど 一緒に帰ろう
It's raining, but let's go home together.
あいつのことばかり いつも思い出して
Always remembering only things about him,
私 明日も 恋してる模様
It seems I'll be in love tomorrow too.
遠くかかる虹 ふわり混ざる夕陽
A distant rainbow, a softly blending sunset.
傘を畳んで 手を繋いだ
Folding the umbrella, we held hands.
幸せもの 今日も 恋空予報
A lucky person, today too, the love sky forecast.
これからもきっと
From now on, I'm sure
晴れのち曇りで雨も降るでしょう
It will be sunny, then cloudy, and then it'll rain too
あいつの笑顔を
At his smiling face,
いつも見とれて
I'm always staring in wonder,
私 本日恋してる
Because today, I'm in love
迷う...
Lost in it...
ずっと
Forever,
このまま恋してたい
I want to keep being in love like this
私
Me
はい！ということで、2曲続けて聴いていただきました！
Alright! So, those were two songs in a row!
イェーイ！
Yay!
いや〜、めちゃくちゃ緊張した！
Man, I was so incredibly nervous!
歌詞間違えてなかったですかね？
I didn't mess up the lyrics, did I?
あ、たぶん、たぶん大丈夫だったと思います！
Ah, I think... I think it was probably fine!
さてね、『GARNET MOON』！
Now then, 'GARNET MOON'!
島みや(えい子)さん大好きかつね、
I love Shimamiya (Eiko)-san, and,
ま、これが主題歌になりましたゲームも大好き、
well, I also love the game this was the theme for,
ということで「いつかライブで歌ってやるぞ」という気持ちで、
so with the feeling of "I'm gonna sing this live someday,"
はい、意気込みで歌いました。難しかったですね！
yes, I sang it with all my heart. It was difficult!
そして『恋空予報』ですね。
And then, 'Koizora Yoho'.
フブキの大好きなボカロ曲でもありまして、
It's one of my favorite Vocaloid songs,
いつかね、何か歌いたいなとか、歌ってみた動画とか出したいなと思ってたんですけど、
and I've always wanted to sing it or put out a cover video,
こうやってね、ライブでやらせていただきました。イェーイ！
and now I finally got to perform it live like this. Yay!
ではでは、ここからはですね、
Now then, from here on out,
コラボパートに移りたいと思います！
I'd like to move on to the collaboration part!
さぁ一体、誰がゲストで来るのでしょうか？
Now then, I wonder just who the guests will be?
お楽しみに！
Look forward to it!
思い通りにいかないことだらけ
With nothing but things not going as planned,
どうしようもなく自己嫌悪
I'm hopelessly stuck in self-loathing
八百万の痛みや悲しみから
From the millions of pains and sorrows,
逃げ込める場所を探してる
I'm searching for a place to escape
いっそ岩の隙間に引きこもって
I might as well shut myself in a cave,
月も太陽も無視して眠ろう
Ignoring the moon and sun and just sleep
生まれてきたことの意味なんて
The meaning of being born into this world...
知らない 分かんないよ
I don't know, I don't understand it
でもそんな風に思えるってことは それは
But the fact that you can feel that way, it means
君がもっともっと素敵になれる
That you have the power to become
力があるって教えてるんだよ
Even more and more wonderful
そうさ 神のまにまに 仰せのままに
That's right, at the will of the gods, just as they say
誰だって地球を愛してる
Everyone loves the Earth
飲めや歌えやどんちゃん騒ぎ
Drink and sing and make a big fuss
たまにはそんなのもいいね
Sometimes that kind of thing is nice too
そうさ 北も南も 右も左も
That's right, North or South, Right or Left
なんだかんだ地球を愛してる
One way or another, we love the Earth
泥んこだけど歩いて行ける
Even if we're covered in mud, we can keep walking
まだまだ先は長いさ
The road ahead is still long
ただただ人でいたいだけ
I just want to be human,
きっと誰もがそう願っているけど
I'm sure everyone wishes for that, but
八百万の心の醜さに
By the ugliness of millions of hearts,
苦しめられる毎日さ
We're tormented every single day
僕が生まれてきたこと
The fact that I was born,
奇跡と言えば聞こえはいいけど
It sounds nice to call it a miracle, but
それはきっと偶然に過ぎなくて
It's surely nothing more than a coincidence,
やっぱり意味なんてないさ
And in the end, there's no meaning to it
でも例えば君に意地悪をする奴が
But for example, if there's someone being mean to you,
居るならそれは君がとっても素敵な人だって
It means that you're an incredibly wonderful person,
教えてるんだよ
And they're just showing it
そうさ 神のまにまに 仰せのままに
That's right, at the will of the gods, just as they say
誰だって地球を愛してる
Everyone loves the Earth
僕が笑って君も笑えば
If I laugh and you laugh too,
許せないことなんてないよ
There's nothing that can't be forgiven
そうさ 男も女も 恋しかるべき
That's right, men and women should fall in love
なんだかんだ地球を愛してる
One way or another, we love the Earth
神のまにまに
Kami no Mani Mani (At the Mercy of the Gods)
自意識は回ってる
Self-consciousness is turning
泥んこだけど歩いて行こう
I'm covered in mud, but let's keep walking
まだまだ先は長いさ
There's still a long way to go
本当に大事なものなんて
Things that are truly important
意外とくだらないことの中にあるよ
Are surprisingly found within trivial things
時にはみんなでバカ騒ぎ
Sometimes, let's all make a fuss together
裸踊りで大笑い
Laughing loudly with a naked dance
大笑い！
Loud laughing!
そうさ 神のまにまに
That's right, at the mercy of the gods
仰せのままに
As they command
もっともっと自分を愛せるよ
You can love yourself more and more
鏡を見てごらんよ
Take a look in the mirror
もう分かるでしょう
You probably already know, right?
みんなを照らす光さ
You're the light that shines on everyone
そうさ 神のまにまに
That's right, at the mercy of the gods
みんなありがとう
Thank you everyone
やっぱり地球を愛してる
After all, I love the Earth
花を咲かそう
Let the flowers bloom
大きな花を
Big flowers
天まで届くくらいの
High enough to reach the heavens
はい！ということで！
Yes! And so!
はい！ミオと、あやめちゃんです！
Yes! It's Mio and Ayame-chan!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ありがとうありがとう！
Thank you, thank you!
今日誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday today!
ありがとう！二人ともー！イエーイ！
Thank you! Both of you! Yay!
おめでたいね。
It's a celebratory occasion.
ということでね、まあ三人といえば百花繚乱なんだけども...
So, speaking of the three of us, we're Hyakka Ryouran...
ま、こないだもね、あやめちゃんのあの誕生日...
Well, just the other day, at Ayame-chan's birthday...
誕生日ライブも、そう！周年記念！
Birthday live, yes! The anniversary!
周年記念だ！
Anniversary!
そうだそうだ！はい、で踊ったので
Right, right! Yes, since we danced then
なんか、三人で別の曲もやってみたいなということで
We thought we'd like to try another song as a trio
神のまにまにを躍らせていただきました！
So we performed Kami no Mani Mani!
イエーイ！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you very much!
和風三人で初めてだよね。
It's the first time for the three of us with the Japanese theme.
ねー！いや本当に。
Right! Yeah, really.
いいね、やっぱこういう曲歌うのも。
It's nice, singing this kind of song too.
たまにはいいですね。
It's good once in a while.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
今日ケーキ食べたの？白上は。
Did you eat cake today, Shirakami?
ケーキまだ食べてない！
I haven't eaten cake yet!
えー！？
Whaaaat!?
じゃ、これ終わったらみんなで食べましょう！
Then let's all eat together after this!
あー！デカいの食べたい！
Ah! I want to eat a big one!
デカいの食べよう！デカいのがいい！
Let's eat a big one! Big is good!
ぜひぜひぜひ。このあともね、まだあのコラボのメンバーいますので
Definitely. After this, there are still collab members...
それ終わったらみんなでケーキ食べて終わりましょう！
After that's over, let's all eat cake and finish up!
やったー！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you very much!
ということで、ミオと、あやめちゃんでした！
So, it was Mio and Ayame-chan!
ありがとう！おめでとう！
Thank you! Congratulations!
ニッポン笑顔百景
Nippon Egao Hyakkei (Japan's Hundred Smiling Views)
よーっ！
Yoh!
寿限無 寿限無 五劫の擦り切れ 海砂利水魚の
Jugemu Jugemu Gokou no Surikire Kaijarisuigyo no
水行末 雲来末 風来末
Suigyomatsu Unraimatsu Furaimatsu
食う寝る処に住む処
Kuuneru tokoro ni sumu tokoro
藪ら柑子の藪柑子
Yaburakouji no yabukouji
パイポパイポ パイポのシューリンガン
Paipo Paipo Paipo no Shuuringan
シューリンガンのグーリンダイ...
Shuuringan no Guurindai...
ちょいと時間頂きます
Please give me a little time
ご清聴ください
Please listen
整いました！
I'm ready!
笑うこととかけまして
Comparing laughing to something...
お祭り野郎と解きます
I solve it as a festival-goer...
その心は、その心は
The reason is, the reason is...
どちらもハッピーになるでしょう！
Both will become happy!
お後がよろしいようで！
And that's that!
笑おう 笑おう さあ笑いましょう
Let's laugh, let's laugh, come on let's laugh
こんな時代こそ笑いましょう
In times like these especially, let's laugh
泣いたって馬鹿だ やけくそ笑いましょう
It's stupid to cry, let's laugh out of desperation
波乱万丈 辛いも甘いも
Ups and downs, bitter and sweet
乗り越えた天晴日本人
Magnificent Japanese who have overcome
笑おう
Let's laugh
どんな時でも何糞笑いましょう
No matter when, let's laugh with all our might
ハハハハ！ワハハハ！
Ha ha ha ha! Wa ha ha ha!
空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ
Don't read the room, just keep laughing
笑顔！笑顔！
Smiles! Smiles!
笑う門には福来たる！
Good fortune comes to those who laugh!
え、皆様、今日はようこそおいで頂きました
Uh, everyone, welcome and thank you for coming today
ここで一首！
Here's a verse!
ネズミの娘がお嫁に行って
A mouse's daughter went to be a bride
じきに帰ってきたんでネズミのお母さんが大変怒って
And came back soon, so the mouse mother was very angry
「あんな良い所へお前嫁いで、誰が嫌で出てきたんだい？」
"You married into such a good place, who did you dislike and come back?"
「いいえ、誰も嫌じゃないんですけれど」
"No, it's not that I disliked anyone..."
ゴインキョさんが優しいんで嫌なの
The retired master is so kind, it's annoying.
優しいんなら結構じゃないかねえ
If he's kind, isn't that nice?
でも猫撫で声ですもの
But he uses a wheedling voice.
忙しさに身を任せて
Letting myself go in the busyness.
消えてゆくだなんてべらぼうめ
Fading away... what a load of nonsense!
笑おう 笑おう 笑えなくても 笑うしかないでしょう 笑いましょう 笑おう
Let's laugh, let's laugh! Even if we can't, we have to laugh, right? Let's laugh, let's laugh!
ソレソレ
Heave-ho, heave-ho!
頬っぺた上げて ひたすら笑いましょう
Raise your cheeks and just keep laughing!
嗚呼、野良運 大引き運さえ
Ah, even if we clear stray luck and big draw luck,
クリアして 現代ニッポン人 笑おう
Modern Japanese people, let's laugh!
未来へいざ往こう
Let's head to the future,
ウハハと笑いましょう
And laugh "uhaha"!
小娘の戯言と 切り捨てないで
Don't dismiss it as a little girl's nonsense.
顰め面なんて変な顔
A scowl is such a strange face,
笑顔が見たいから
Because I want to see your smile.
笑おう 笑おう さあ笑いましょう こんな時代こそ 笑いましょう 笑おう
Let's laugh, let's laugh! Come on, let's laugh! In times like these, let's laugh, let's laugh!
ソレソレ
Heave-ho, heave-ho!
泣いた挙げ句の焼け糞 笑いましょう
After crying, even in desperation, let's laugh!
波瀾万丈 酸いも甘いも
Through life's ups and downs, overcoming bitter and sweet,
乗り越えた アッパレニッポン人 笑おう
Splendid Japanese people, let's laugh!
どんな武器でも 何クソ 笑いましょう
Whatever the weapon, whatever happens, let's laugh!
ひたすら笑いましょう
Just keep on laughing!
ワハハ ワハハ
Wahahaha, wahahaha!
ヌハハ ヌハハ
Nuhahaha, nuhahaha!
空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ
Don't worry about reading the room, just laugh!
笑顔 笑顔 笑顔 笑顔
Smile, smile, smile, smile!
笑う門には福来たる
Fortune comes to those who smile!
はい！
Yes!
どうもどうもー！
Hello, hello!
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you very much!
はい、ゲーマーズで「ニッポン笑顔百景」でした！
Yes, that was "Nippon Egao Hyakkei" by Gamers!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ということで、なんとゲーマーズお久しぶりでございます。
So, it's been a while since Gamers were together.
そうですね！お久しぶりでございます。
That's right! It's been a while.
ゲーマーズって知ってますか？
Do you know Gamers?
知ってるよ！知ってる知ってる！
We know! We know, we know!
知ってる？知ってる？
Know it? Know it?
ホロライブゲーマーズ知ってるよねー、知ってる。
You know Hololive Gamers, right? We know.
じゃあホロライブゲーマーズは何期と何期の間にあるグループでしょうか？
Then, between which generations is Hololive Gamers situated?
あー、これめっちゃ聞かれるやつ！
Oh, people ask this all the time!
やばいやばい。これ超聞かれるやつだよ。
Oh no, oh no. This is a very common question.
正解はちなみに、正解は2期と3期の間でした！
By the way, the correct answer is between the 2nd and 3rd generations!
イェーイ！
Yay!
つまり、2.5期生ということで。
In other words, we're the 2.5 generation.
2.5期生だー！
2.5 generation!
ということで今回ですね、お集まりいただきましたけど、おかゆ！
So, we've gathered here today, but Okayu!
おかゆも10月1日お誕生日でね！
Okayu's birthday was also October 1st!
おめでとー！
Congratulations!
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you very much!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
でもでもでもでも！
But, but, but, but!
何？
What?
今日はフブキちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Today is Fubuki-chan's birthday, congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
本当に集まってくれてありがとうね、みんな。
Thank you all so much for coming together.
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
一番最初さ、寝てたよね？めっちゃ。
At the very beginning, you were sleeping, right? A lot.
いやいやいや。別に、あれは他意があるわけではないんですよ。
No, no, no. There was no ulterior motive for that.
ほんとに？
Really?
ネハン、ネハン。
Nehan, nehan.
ネハン、ネハンって何？ネハン。
Nehan? What's "nehan"?
罪の名前？それ。
Is that the name of a sin?
ネハン。知らない？むしろ、むしろ罪の逆だと思うな。
Nehan. You don't know it? I think it's the opposite of a sin.
そう、平和みたいな意味があるんじゃないかな？
Yeah, doesn't it have a meaning like peace?
あ、平和。助かる。平和助かる。
Oh, peace. That helps. Peace is good.
全然オッケーですよ。いや、まじこうして本当にね、ゲーマーズ集まれて本当よかったです。ありがとうございました。
It's totally okay. No, I'm really glad we could get the Gamers together like this. Thank you so much.
こちらこそー！
Likewise!
またゲームとかしても遊びましょう！
Let's play some games or something again!
遊びましょう！
Let's play!
ということで、ゲーマーズでしたー！
So, that was the Gamers!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
Congrats Birthday FOX
Shirakami Fubuki / Happy Birthday 2021
フィクサー / 作詞・作曲: ぬゆり
Fixer / Lyrics & Composition: nulut
今日までの記憶の 全部を消してしまう時まで 眠れない
Until the time when I erase all the memories up to today, I can't sleep.
明日じゃない　昨日でもない　自分のみがわりが欲しくてたまらない
Not tomorrow, nor yesterday, I'm dying for a surrogate of myself.
大丈夫と言い捨てて　後から君のせいにさせてはくれないか
Saying "it's fine" and leaving, won't you let me blame it on you later?
今更意味ないから　後から君のせいにさせてはくれないか
It's pointless now, so won't you let me blame it on you later?
出来ない約束を　とうとうと溢れる　一言一言ばかりに　脳を暴かれるくらい
To the point where my brain is being exposed by word after word of overflowing impossible promises.
意味をなさない　何も出来ない　見えない　逃げたい　跳びたい　やめたい　逸らせない
Meaningless, can't do anything, can't see, want to run, want to jump, want to stop, can't look away.
だから沈め　沈め　這い上がれないほどまで
So sink, sink, to the point where you can't crawl back up.
飽きるまで　踊らせて　どうせ　救い垂らす時まで
Let me dance until I'm bored, at least until the moment salvation is granted.
嘘味の粒々を　喉から絞め出して悲鳴ごと噛み砕く
Squeezing out lie-flavored grains from my throat, crushing them along with the screams.
笑顔が痛むばかりで　じっと唇に手を当て過ごす
My smile just hurts, so I spend time with my hand pressed against my lips.
なりたくなかった　今日役立つな　虚ろで眠たい理想で　救われることを待つ
I didn't want to become this, don't be useful today, waiting to be saved by hollow, sleepy ideals.
一番目は今の口代わりを　力強く硬く痛く噛み締めて
First, strongly, hard, and painfully bite down on the current scapegoat.
死んでしまえ　しまえ　この先も過去を知らず
Just die, die, without knowing the future or the past.
嫌いなら　壊せ　壊せ　どうせなら加害者になればいい
If you hate it, break it, break it, you might as well become the perpetrator.
戦わない　苛立ちも　何も生まない悲しみも
Neither the irritation from not fighting, nor the sadness that produces nothing.
味気なくて　吐き出す前に　もう　次を歌え
It's tasteless, before spitting it out, sing the next one already.
どうせなら　踊り踊れ　灰色になり切る前に
At least dance, dance, before becoming completely gray.
打ち鳴らせ　変われ変われ　眠りに落ちる時まで
Ring it out, change, change, until the moment you fall asleep.
どうせなら　奪え奪え　飼い馴らした嘘を暴いて
At least take it, take it, exposing the tamed lies.
煮え滾る　頭に過った　虚像を　見ていた
Watching the virtual image that crossed my boiling mind.
自分を見ていた
I was watching myself.
Feuer sperre! Feuer los! Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
戦場へ出ろ　兵士として死の淵まで　命捨てた　その覚悟を示せ
Go to the battlefield! As a soldier, to the brink of death, show the resolve to discard your life.
聞こえるだろう　あの放戦が　成功をする　凱歌の声だ
You can hear it, right? That artillery fire, it's the sound of a successful victory song.
踏み潰せ　踏み潰せ
Trample them down! Trample them down!
Feuer sperre! Feuer los! Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
散々のアメに　打たれ行くのか　硝煙千番　国の為だ
Will you go through the terrible rain of bullets? A thousand gunsmoke trials, it's for the country.
戦場へ出ろ　兵士として死の淵まで　命捨てた　覚悟を示せよ
Go to the battlefield! As a soldier, to the brink of death, show the resolve to discard your life.
忠誠を自由を捧げて　その魂を　すべて捧げ　勝ち鬨を上げよう
Dedicate your loyalty and freedom, give all of that soul, and let's raise a victory shout.
さあ誇り　築いてみせろ　天に轟く一閃を
Now, show that you can build pride, a flash of light that roars to the heavens.
Feuer sperre! Feuer los! Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los! Achtung! Die Deckung hoch!
Fire! Barrage! Go! Attention! Get your cover up!
どこに恐怖があるというのだ
Where is there any fear?
身の血肉が花火のようだ
My flesh and blood are like fireworks
撒き散らす
Scattered
惨の傷はど忘れしちゃいなさい
Just forget about those tragic wounds
炎の熱も溢れ出すと思う
The heat of the flames will overflow
最期の呻きも濁った瞳も
Even the final groans and those clouded eyes
ああそれこそを求めるのだ
Ah, that's exactly what I seek
愛も平和も混ぜ合わいなんて
Love and peace mixed together?
暇を捨てた飼い犬の証拠を
Proof of a stray dog who abandoned its leisure
絶望と野良を駆けた極彩左輪
The multicolored revolver that ran through despair and the wild
地獄よりも楽園のようだ
It's more like paradise than hell
さあ血潮はあがるために
Now, the lifeblood is for rising up
狂い狂うためにあるのだ
It exists for the sake of going mad
人間に価値などない、価値なき者同士の争いに、命の仇花を咲かせてみせろ
Humans have no value. In a conflict between valueless beings, show me how the blossoms of life can bloom!
凍り付いた秩序でも
Even in a frozen order
狂ったやつが創ってる
It's created by those who've gone mad
マカニファルス不条理だけの
Makanifarus, only absurdity
起承転結
Introduction, development, twist, and conclusion
全土へ出征そして地の果てまで
Going to war across the whole land, to the ends of the earth
命捨てた覚悟示せよ
Show your resolve to throw away your life
銃声を呪いをしてその魂を
With the sound of gunshots as a curse, take that soul
全て捧げ勝鬨をあげよ
Sacrifice everything and raise a victory cry
さあここに築いてみせよ
Now, show me what you've built here
天に届く人柱に
As a human pillar reaching the heavens
谺する憎しみさえ
Even the echoing hatred
かき消す爆発音
The sound of the explosion drowns it out
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los! Achtung! Die Deckung hoch!
Fire! Barrage! Go! Attention! Get your cover up!
Congrats Birthday FOX
Shirakami Fubuki | Happy Birthday 2021
進め! BAKATARATION
作詞: 真崎エリカ 作曲: 本多友紀 編曲: 脇眞富
Susume! BAKATARATION
Lyrics: Erika Masaki Composition: Yuki Honda Arrangement: Masatomi Waki
新しい時代進んでく私たち
We who advance into a new era
みんなで進もう！
Let's all advance together!
朝まで騒ごうよ　悪くはないよね
Let's make some noise until morning, it's not bad, right?
悪くはないよね！
It's not bad, is it!
世界揺らせるくらい強い絆の中で
Within a bond strong enough to shake the world
ひとつになって Go!
Become one and Go!
Oh yes!
3, 2, 1, バカタレーション！
3, 2, 1, Bakataration!
楽しんじゃえ最高に (バカタレ！)
Let's enjoy it to the max (Bakatare!)
掲げてよね　万歳 (バカタレ！)
Hold it high, Banzai! (Bakatare!)
モヤモヤも全部投げっしょ (バカタレ！)
Throw away all your worries (Bakatare!)
私たちがナンバーワン (バカタレ！)
We are number one (Bakatare!)
ワクワクはずーっと続いていくよ (わっしょーい！)
The excitement will continue forever (Wassho-i!)
初めての扉さあドンドン開けていこう
Let's keep opening new doors
怖がらずにいこう！
Let's go without being afraid!
ついつい夜更かしでも一人じゃないよね
Even if we stay up late, we're not alone, right?
一人じゃないよね！
We're not alone, are we!
迷ってもいいよだって寄り道もイベントだし
It's okay to get lost, because detours are also events
前のめり Go!
Leaning forward, Go!
Oh yes!
まだまだ　バカタレーション！
Still Bakataration!
駆け抜けてこうオールウェイズ (バカタレ！)
Let's run through it, always (Bakatare!)
はしゃぎながらオールデイズ (バカタレ！)
While frolicking, all days (Bakatare!)
ノリノリで乗りこなせ最高潮 (バカタレ！)
Ride it with high spirits to the climax (Bakatare!)
地球は広いけど回ると一緒 (バカタレ！)
The earth is wide, but it's the same as it spins (Bakatare!)
ドタバタはずーっと続いていくよ (わっしょーい！)
The slapstick fun will continue forever (Wassho-i!)
フブちゃーん！
Fubu-chaaan!
おい！
Hey!
誕生日だってー！
It's your birthday!
そうだよ！
That's right!
おめでとー！
Happy birthday!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
そしてこの曲はなーに！
And what is this song!
バカタれのオリ曲だよ！
It's Bakatare's original song!
いいかー！
Is it good!?
わっしょーい！
Wassho-i!
ほらー！
Hora-!
わっしょーい！
Wassho-i!
ほらー！
Hora-!
いやもう本当にね、こうやってバカタれのオリ曲作ってもらえて白上とっても嬉しいよ！
No, really, I'm so happy to have an original song for Bakatare!
私も嬉しい！
I'm happy too!
嬉しい！
Happy!
嬉しいよね！
Happy, right!
今後もずっとバカタれなんだなー！
We'll be Bakatare forever!
バカタレ最高！
Bakatare is the best!
遊び足りない日は
On days when we haven't played enough,
もう少しいっしょに
let's stay together a little longer.
（もっともっといっしょに）
(More and more together)
みんなでときめく
Our heart-pounding
無敵の友情
invincible friendship,
未来へと振りかざして
hold it high towards the future!
さぁ進め バカタレーション
Now, onwards, BAKATARATION!
楽しんじゃえサイコー！
Let's have the best time!
撫でてよネッタプ
Stroke it, Net-up!
今夜も踊りおまけテンションで！
Tonight as well, dancing with extra high spirits!
私たちがナンバーワン！
We are number one!
いつだってオンステージ
Always on stage.
これまでも ここからも
Until now, and from now on too,
ワクワク続いていくよ
the excitement will continue!
はーい！
Hi!
ということで、突然で皆さんびっくりしたと思いますけども
So, I think everyone was surprised by the sudden announcement...
なんと！ この度、バカタレどものオリジナル楽曲ができました！
Believe it or not! An original song for us, 'Bakatare', has been made!
イエーイ！ やったー！
Yay! We did it!
フブちゃんのお誕生日プレゼントってこと？
So it's a birthday present for Fubu-chan?
えっ、そういうことなのこれって？
Eh, is that what this is?
そういうことさ！
That's exactly it!
そういうことだったの？ なるほど
Is that so? I see.
誕生日にもらっちゃいました、いや嬉しいですね！
I received it for my birthday, I'm so happy!
こっそり準備してたじゃないか、ね、一緒にみんなで
We were secretly preparing it, right? All of us together.
ということで今回は『進め！BAKATARATION』ということでね、オリ曲を！
So this time, it's 'Onwards! BAKATARATION', our original song!
はい、作ってみんなで躍らせていただきました！
Yes, we made it and performed the dance together!
全員バラバラの方角向いてるが…ｗ
We're all facing different directions though... lol
あっち！ あっち！ あっち！
That way! That way! That way!
はい、こちらの楽曲ですね、MVとかね、発売とかは…
Yes, about this song, the MV and the release...
あ、もちろん、もちろんするんですけども！
Ah, of course, of course we will!
今ね、運営さんたちと相談しながら制作中でございますので
We're currently in the middle of production while consulting with the staff.
はい、聴きたい方はぜひともまたこのライブのアーカイブを見直していただいて
So if you want to hear it, please rewatch the archive of this live,
覚えてもらって、いつかはライブでやるぞ！
memorize it, and someday we'll perform it at a live concert!
いつかはバカタレライブでこの曲を歌いたいと思います、また！
I want to sing this song again at a Bakatare live concert someday!
まだまだバカタレ、目が離せませんよ！
Don't take your eyes off Bakatare yet!
ということで皆さんありがとうございました、バカタレどもでした！
So, thank you everyone, we were Bakatare!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
この胸に あの日君が蒔いた
In this heart, you sowed on that day
小さな涙の種
a small seed of tears.
いつか大きな笑顔の花
Someday, a large flower of smiles
咲かせるその日まで
until the day I make it bloom...
目まぐるしい毎日の中までも
Even in the midst of dizzying days,
ときどき不意に巻き戻してる
sometimes I'm suddenly rewinding.
あの先もずっと君といられたら
If I could be with you forever beyond that,
もしもの未来
a 'what if' future.
どこにもいない姿を
Your figure that is nowhere to be found,
どこにいても感じたまま
I still feel it no matter where I am.
今日も同じ空の下で
Today as well, under the same sky,
明日へと向かうよ
I'm heading towards tomorrow.
繰り返す言葉はそうまるで
The repeated words are almost like
心を溶かすように
they are melting my heart.
僕に今 語りかけるんだ
They are talking to me now
愛おしいその声で
with that beloved voice.
この胸に あの日君が蒔いた
In this heart, you sowed on that day
小さな涙の種
a small seed of tears.
いつか大きな笑顔の花
Someday, a large flower of smiles
咲かせるその日まで
until the day I make it bloom.
ここにいるから
Because I am here.
特別すぎる事ではなくて
It's not about things that are too special,
やがて誰もがその意味を知る
soon everyone will know the meaning.
赤く燃え尽きる雲の切れ間には
In the gaps of the clouds burning out red,
星が瞬く
stars twinkle.
その瞳は今どこで
Where are those eyes now,
どんな景色を見てるの
what kind of scenery are they looking at?
君が好きだった季節が
The season you liked
また巡ってくるよ
is coming around again.
抱きしめた君のカケラたちが
The pieces of you I held close
何も変わらないままで
remain just as they were,
何度でも語りかけるんだ
speaking to me over and over again
愛しいその声で
with that beloved voice.
忘れない あの日君がまいた
I won't forget the tiny seed of tears
小さな涙の種
that you sowed that day.
いつか大きな笑顔の花
One day, a great flower of smiles
咲かせるその日まで
until the day it blooms,
ここにいるから
I'll be right here.
朝も昼も夜も
Morning, noon, and night,
見つけながら迷いながら
while searching, while getting lost,
僕らは約束の場所へ
we hurry to the promised place.
急ぐ
We hurry.
繰り返す言葉はそうまるで
The words I repeat, it's as if
心を溶かすように
they're melting my heart.
僕に今 語りかけるんだ
They're speaking to me now
愛しいその声で
with that beloved voice.
この胸に あの日君がまいた
The tiny seed of tears that you sowed
小さな涙の種
in this heart that day.
やっと大きな笑顔の花
Finally, I could make
咲かせたんだ
a great flower of smiles bloom.
きっといつでも
Surely, always,
ここにいるから
I'll be right here.
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
よっしゃー！まだまだいくぞー！
Alright! Let's keep going!
フー！フー！
Woo! Woo!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
皆さんもいっぱいサイリウム振ってくださいね！
Everyone, please wave your penlights a lot!
逃げたりあきらめることは
Running away or giving up
だれも
is something anyone
一瞬あればできるから
can do in a split second,
歩き続けよう
so let's keep on walking.
君にしかできないことがある
There's something only you can do,
青い星に光がなくせぬように
so the light on this blue planet isn't lost.
つかめ！描いた夢を
Grasp it! The dream you drew.
まもれ！大事な友を
Protect it! Your precious friend.
たくましい自分になれるさ
You can become a strong version of yourself.
知らないパワーが宿る
An unknown power resides within.
ハートに火がついたら
Once the fire is lit in your heart,
どんな願いも 嘘じゃない
any wish you have is not a lie.
きっとかなうから
Because it will surely come true.
show me your brave heart
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey!
皆もよかったら一緒に歌ってねー！
Everyone, please sing along if you like!
晴れの日ばかりじゃないから
Because it's not always sunny days,
たまに
sometimes
冷たい雨も降るけれど
cold rain will fall, too,
傘広げよう
but let's open our umbrellas.
生き方に地図なんかないけど
There's no map for our way of life,
だから自由
but that's why we're free.
どこへだって行ける
We can go anywhere.
君も
You too.
走れ！風より速く
Run! Faster than the wind.
めざせ！空より遠く
Aim! Further than the sky.
新しい自分に会えるさ
You can meet a new version of yourself.
知らない勇気が眠る
An unknown courage sleeps within.
ハートに気がついたら
Once you notice it in your heart...
魚の
Fish's...
ドシャ降りにも
Even in a downpour
きっと止むから
it will surely stop.
Show me your brave heart
つかめ　眩しい明日を
Grasp the dazzling tomorrow
守れ　愛する人を
Protect the ones you love
たくましい自分に　なれるさ
You can become a strong person
壊せ　弱気な君を
Break your timid self
崩せ　ぶつかる壁を
Destroy the walls you hit
熱い鼓動　武器になるから
Because your hot heartbeat will become your weapon
Believe in your heart
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
本当皆さん、今日はありがとね！
Really everyone, thank you for today!
ありがとうだよー！
Thank you!
はい！ということで、2曲続けて聴いていただきました！ありがとうございます！
Yes! So, you've heard two songs in a row! Thank you very much!
はい、『涙の種、笑顔の花』ですね。
Yes, that was "Seed of Tears, Flower of Smiles".
白上1期生のライブの時には『空色デイズ』を歌わせていただいたんですけど、
At my 1st gen live, I sang "Sorairo Days",
まあそれも相まって今回は『涙の種、笑顔の花』、しょこたん大好きです！イエーイ！
so combined with that, this time I chose "Seed of Tears, Flower of Smiles". I love Shokotan! Yay!
そしてですね、『brave heart』は一昨年になっちゃうのかな？
And as for "brave heart", was it the year before last?
もう、白上のお誕生日イベントでですね、『Butter-Fly』を歌わせていただきましたので、
At my birthday event, I sang "Butter-Fly",
今回は『brave heart』仕様ということで、皆さん進化しましたか？大丈夫ですか？(笑)
so this time it was the "brave heart" version. Did you guys evolve? Are you okay? (laughs)
はい！では次で最後の曲なんですけども、ここでお知らせです！
Yes! The next one will be the last song, but first, an announcement!
なんと！なんと！ただいま開催中の富士急ハイランドさんにて、
Wow! Wow! At Fuji-Q Highland, which is currently holding an event,
10月5日、今日から10日まで、の期間限定で白上の限定ボイスが聞けちゃいまーす！
from today, October 5th until the 10th, you can hear my limited-time voice for a limited period!
そしてなんと！メリーゴーランドも白上の『Say!ファンファーレ!』が流れちゃいますので、ぜひ皆さん来てください！お願いしまーす！
And what's more! "Say! Fanfare!" will be playing on the carousel too, so please come visit! Please!
そしてもう一個！なんと！なんと！明日、
And one more thing! Wow! Tomorrow,
明日はですね、白上の誕生日、後夜祭ということで、
since tomorrow is my birthday after-party,
Live2Dの、頭かな？横かな？なんだろうな？アクセサリーが追加されます！
some accessories will be added to my Live2D model! On the head? On the side? I wonder what they are?
そして、グッズも明日告知させていただこうと思いますので、よろしくお願いします！
And I'll also be announcing some goods tomorrow, so please look forward to it!
明日も見るんじゃぞい！
Make sure to watch tomorrow too!
ではでは、本当に本当に次で最後の曲でございます。
Now then, the next song really, really is the last one.
それでは、聴いてください。『Say!ファンファーレ!』
Now, please listen. "Say! Fanfare!"
皆さん！最後の曲『Say!ファンファーレ!』行きますよー！うっ！と！
Everyone! Here we go with the last song, "Say! Fanfare!"! Utto!
イエーイ！ハイ！ハイ！うっ！とっ！そっ！
Yay! Hi! Hi! Utto so!
Say!ファンファーレ!
作詞・作曲・編曲：tilt-six (Foxtail-Grass Studio)
Say! Fanfare!
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: tilt-six (Foxtail-Grass Studio)
Are you ready?
はーっとひといきお茶ですよ
Take a deep breath and have some tea
（はい！どうぞ！）いつもの場所から
(Here you go!) From the usual place
元気にせーのでご挨拶（おはこんですー！）始めましょう！
Greet everyone energetically on the count of three (Oha-kon!) Let's begin!
お喋りをしてゲームと過ごす　そんな毎日が愛しくて
Chatting and playing games, I cherish every day like that
あれもこれも手を出したくなり勝ちです
I tend to want to try this and that
歌とかステージはまだまだ恥ずかしいけど
Singing and being on stage is still a bit embarrassing
支え合ってほら届けますよ　この声を
Supporting each other, look, I'll deliver this voice
Say！　ほらその顔上げて　みんなで手を取れば　バンザイ！
Say! Look up, and if we all take each other's hands, banzai!
まだまだ道の中途　世界を変えよう
We're still in the middle of our journey, let's change the world
Say！　ほらお仕事も　止まらない全力ですから
Say! Look, even work, I'm going at full power without stopping
夢を書き換えたら　追いかけ続けよう　共に繋ぐファンファーレ
If we rewrite our dreams, let's keep chasing them, the fanfare that connects us together
イエーイ！ハイ！ハイ！うっ！とっ！そっ！
Yay! Hi! Hi! Utto so!
（フー！）せーの！Go Go Let's Go!
(Fu-!) Ready! Go Go Let's Go!
ちょーっとやらかした時でも（もう大丈夫！）気持ち切り替えて
Even when I mess up a little (It's okay now!) Switch your feelings
ぼーっとしちゃう昼下がりは（昼コンですよー！）背伸びをして
In the early afternoon when I'm spacing out (Hiru-kon!) Stretch a little
お腹減ったらすぐモグモグと　お茶の合間すこんなおやつで
When I'm hungry, I eat immediately, snacks like this during tea time
黒いあの子には内緒にしてほしいです
I'd like to keep it a secret from that black one.
仲間の力と
With the help of my friends
お友達のみなさんと
and all of you.
叶えたい想いは
Turning my wishes
言葉にして
into words,
一つ一つ
each and every one.
Say! ほらその手を上げて
Say! Hey, raise your hands!
みんなで輪になればポイ！
If everyone gets in a circle, poi!
まだまだ成長中！ もったいないでしょ？
I'm still growing! Isn't it a waste?
Say! ほら明るく元気な
Say! Hey, my bright and energetic
心が取り柄ですから
heart is my best trait.
凹みがちな時も
Even when I'm feeling down,
輝き続けよう
let's keep on shining.
共に繋ぐアンコール
The encore we join together.
Say! Fanfare!
Go! Go! Let's go!
何もかもがあたらしくて
Everything was so new,
右も左もわからない時も
and I didn't know left from right.
頑張れたのは一人じゃないから
I could do my best because I wasn't alone.
一つ一つ応援が後押しになって
Every bit of support gave me a push,
一歩進んでも
and even as I take a step forward...
私は自分らしく磨いていく Future
I'll keep polishing the future in my own way.
答えもイメージも
Even if the answers and images
まだまだ手探りしても
are still a work in progress.
響き合ってほら
Resonating together, look,
世界は今色めいて
the world is now coming to life with color.
Say! さあその顔上げて
Say! Now, lift your head,
みんなで手を取れば Dive!
if we all take each other's hands, Dive!
これからの夢の先へ 駆け出そう！
Let's run toward the future of our dreams!
Say! ほら汗も涙も
Say! Look, sweat and tears,
止まらない全力ですから
it's because I'm going at full power.
大好きな思いが
My feelings of love
溢れそうなほど
are almost overflowing.
共に繋ぐファンファーレ
The fanfare we join together.
みなさん、本当にありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much!
みんな、大好きだぞー！
Everyone, I love you!
いぇーい！
Yay!